The other day I told you about the center of Christ
那天我告诉你们 关于基督的能量中心
and center of Shri Krishna
和锡吕克里希纳的中心
and their relationship with each other.
以及他们之间的关系
Now the last and the most important
我们体内最后的 也是最重要的
one within us is the center of Sahasrara is the limbic area.
能量中心是顶轮 是一个边缘区域
When you enter into it you become thoughtlessly aware.
当你进入它 你变得无思虑的觉醒
This is the area to be entered through the Kundalini,
这个区域 通过灵量来进入
through the center of Christ,
通过基督的能量中心
through the Gate of Christ and that's why is written
通过基督的大门 这也是为什么
that you have to enter through Him.
有记载你们必须 通过他来进入
But not by somebody else saying, "I'm the Christ" or
但并不是某人说 我就是基督
saying, "I profess Christ and Christ"
或宣称我信奉基督 和基督教
It's not that way. Christ is within us
不是这种方式 基督存在于我们之内
and when the Kundalini rises,
当灵量升起
if it stops at this center,
如果在此轮穴停止
you have to take His name. Not
你必须念诵他的名号
then only the Kundalini pierces through that center of Christ,
只有当灵量 穿过基督的轮穴
that's the door, that's the gate He's talked about,
那是门户 那就是他说的大门
and then you enter into the Kingdom of God.
那时你便进入了 神的国度
"Thou shalt inherit the Kingdom of God." Inherit.
你们继承神的国度
That's your Father's Kingdom
那是你们父的天国
and that you have to inherit.
这就是你们必须继承的
But now the most important is the last center of Sahasrara.
但是现在最重要的是 最后一个轮穴--顶轮
When you have all the seven centers placed one after another,
当你有这一个又一个的七个轮穴
these centers are really the seats
这些能量中心确实
The seats are in the brain,
宝座在大脑中
their aura is around the heart
它们的光环围绕着心脏
but they are actually sleeping in the
但是实际上它们 是在我们叫做Sthanas
"Sthanas" as we call, the places of centers.
的地方沉睡着
So, it is in three ways you can understand. One,
因此 你可以用三种方式理解它
in the brain, there are seven centers of the seats
第一，在大脑中 有七个能量中心的宝座
and their auras are falling on the heart.
它们的光环落在心脏上
Their places are in the center.
它们位于能量中心
And the first stage of the awakening of the Kundalini
唤醒灵量的第一个阶段
only these Deities get awakened.
只有这些神得以唤醒
That means when you chant any word or you call Them by name,
那意味着当你唱赞歌 或你呼唤他们的名字
They react. In the sense They open the chakras. You can
他们做出反应 在这个意义上他们打开轮穴
clearly with your own eyes the Kundalini rising through them.
清楚地看到灵量升起 并穿过这些轮穴
Then later on, when you grow more and more,
然后 当你有了更多的成长
these Deities leave Their places and occupy Their seats
这些神祇离开他们的所在的 能量中心的位置 来到他们的宝座之上
and even the Spirit, which is in the heart,
甚至是灵 它位于心脏的位置
comes up here
它升起来到这里
on the fontanel bone area where there is the heart,
囱门骨区所在的地方 这里是心脏
seat of the heart center, which is the heart here, opened goes there.
心能量中心的宝座 心轮打开来到那里
But it is at a much later state,
但是这是在 更晚些时候的状态
that state at a much later time, we can say much later
这个状态是在更晚些时候 我们可以说它是你头脑
state of your mind it's a,
在很久以后的状态
you get into that speed
你进入那个速度之中
in which you just achieve that state.
你只是到达这样的状态
It is an achievement.
这是一项成就
It cannot be a false certificate from somebody or one can say this is written
它不可能是来自某人的假证书
There's no calculation like that.
没有这样的计算
It has to mature in its living way
它必须以它自己 活生生的方式得以成熟
and you yourself will know
你自己也将会知道
that you have got now complete Self-realization.
你已得到完全的自觉
First thing you get is thoughtless awareness.
你得到的第一件事 是无思虑的意识
With this you cross the Gate of Christ.
通过它你穿越基督的门
You can cure people, you can raise the Kundalini.
你可以治愈别人 你可以提升灵量
You may also be able to give Realization to people.
你也可能可以 给予其他人自觉
But still you are capable of falling out.
但是你仍然 有可能会跌落
Supposing somebody, a person comes
假设某个人
with negative forces and fanaticism
他带着负面能量 和狂热来到这里
he may encompass you. And you may go down.
他可能会包围你 你可能会下降
But the second state is called as the doubtless awareness.
第二个阶段 被称作无疑惑的意识
If you rise into that then you have no doubts whatsoever.
如果你升进到这个阶段 你了无疑惑
You never fall down. Maybe your Kundalini comes and goes and
你不会下降 可能你的灵量来了又走了
supplies and sometimes you can feel the catches, it's all right.
并且有时候你感到被感染 这没有关系
But after that,
但是在这之后
you are so sure of yourself
你对你自己
and of your achievement, your Self-Realization that you never falloff.
你的成就 和你的自觉如此确定 你从不下降
But the last one is the very important thing
但是最后一个 是最重要的事情
where many Sahaja yogis also falter,
在这个阶段许多 霎哈嘉瑜伽士也会动摇
is the integration.
那就是整合
For example, a somebody's born a Christian,
比如说 一个人出生时是个基督徒
he's born.
他的出生
He could have been born a Hindu; he could have been born anything.
他可以出生时是印度徒 他可以在出生时 是任何宗教教徒
He could have been Muslim.
他可能生为穆斯林
Muslim I have seen one fanatic,
我见过一位狂热的穆斯林
like a Muslim if he a fanatic he is
像穆斯林一样 若他是狂热分子
born today as a fanatic Hindu
他出生为一位 狂热的印度教徒
or a fanatic Christian,
或者一位狂热的基督徒
these are all fanatics.
他们都是狂热者
They go from one swing to another swing and they profess.
他们熟练地跳 从一个秋千到另一个秋千摆动
He will have Koran in his hand,
他会手持可兰经
this fellow will have Bible in his hand and another will have Gita in his hand,
这人会手持圣经 而另一人会手持薄伽梵歌
three of them are fighting.
三人都在争斗
He says I'm correct, he says I'm correct and he says I'm correct.
他说我是正确的 而另一人说我是正确的
Now what is the authority?
那么什么是权威呢
Even of these books people will ask what is the authority of the Bible.
甚至对于这些书籍人们会问 什么是圣经的权威
What is the authority of the Gita
什么是薄伽梵歌的权威
and what is the authority of the Koran?
而什么是可兰经的权威呢
They'll say what is the authority of The Old Testament?
他们会问什么 是旧约的权威呢
If they ask authority, what is the answer?
如果人们质疑权威性 回答是什么呢
And you can ask what is my authority?
你可以问什么是我的权威呢
You must ask this question.
你应该问这个问题
In the beginning people do ask what is my authority.
开始时人们确实 问什么是我的权威
My authority is that I give you Realization.
我的权力就是给你们自觉
And you ask the question, "Mother are you the authority?"
你们问 母亲你是权威么
you get vibrations.
你获得生命能量
This is my authority.
这就是我的权力
Then you will understand why Bible is right, Koran is right and Gita is right.
这样你会明白为何圣经是对的 古兰经是对的、薄伽梵歌是对的
Because of the narrow vision we have.
因为我们视野局限
If they are born as a Christian then they'll stick into it.
如果他们生为基督徒 那么就会固守它
If you are Catholics you will be Protestants, if you are
如果你是天主教 你会变成新教徒
Protestants you'll become
如果你是新教徒 你会变成
a 7th Day Adventist, Pentecostals,
耶稣第七天复活论者 五旬节派
this that, born again, this that nonsense
这个那个，重生 这个或那个荒唐的事
we go on ending up like that in a Christian genealogy,
我们最终形成了 基督教的宗谱
from one madness to another madness achieving nothing,
从一种疯狂变成另一种疯狂 什么也没得到
believing into some sort of a theoretical thing
相信着 某种理论上的东西
like 7th Day Adventist.
例如七天复活论
I can't understand it.
我无法理解
These theories and these things are not going to give you
这些理论和 这些事情不能给予你
living experience,
活生生的经验
which is beyond rationality, which is beyond mind,
这种经验是超越理性 超越思维
which is Baptism, the real sense of the word,
是一种洗礼 是这个词的真正意思
where you get this breeze in the hand, of the Holy Spirit.
你在手中获得凉风 是圣洁的灵
But we want to play about with these things with our narrow visions now see
但是我们想玩把戏 以我们狭隘的视野
one case of Christ.
基督是一个例子
Christ was definitely, as I told you, was
基督是绝对的 我告诉过你们
Pranava, Omkara, everything was there,
他是Pranava Omkara 所有一切都在那
no doubt.
毫无疑问
But when He was born,
当他出生时
there was signs and everything.
有各种迹象 各种事情
Despite all that there was a king who wanted to kill Him.
除此之外 有一位国王想杀他
See the negativity. No intellectual accepted Him.
看看这些负面 没有知识分子接受他
No bureaucrat accepted Him,
没有一个官僚接受他
no educated person accepted Him.
没有一个 受过教育的人接受他
He had to actually beg of those
他不得不祈求
very ordinary, mediocre people
这些非常普通的平凡的
like fishermen to come and become His disciples.
像渔夫这样的人 来成为他的门徒
See the situation.
看这个情形
And He was allowed to live
这些可怕的人 只允许他活4年
They may be born today as Christians and must be saying we are
他们可能在今天 作为基督徒出生
Christians and Christ and Christ and Christ.
他们可能说 我们是基督徒
That's why Christ has said I will not recognize you.
这是为什么耶稣基督说 我将不会承认你们
They might be the people who might have crucified Christ.
他们可能是那些将耶稣基督 钉在十字架上的人
And they're again crucifying Him
现在他们通过否认这活生生 上帝的活生生的力量
by denying the living force of the living God.
而再次将耶稣钉在十字架上
Four years.
4年
Now, what can you do in four years? I told you
现在，在4年里 你们能做什么
four years, with all my powers, I was struggling with six hippies
我告诉你们，4年 我带着我所有的力量 挣扎于给伦敦6个嬉皮士以自觉
He never even thought of giving Realization because He thought
耶稣从没想过给予自觉
Whatever He said,
无论他说什么
He said it very precise and deep.
他说的都非常精确和深入
If anything that is narrow has to be deep.
如果任何事情是狭窄的 那么它必须是深入的
Which cannot go into the heads of people who just listen to
这些进入不了 那些人的脑子里去
sermons and lectures
这些人只听从说教和演讲
and read books and sort of have big theories built up into anything.
以及看书
It will only be possible when you get your Realization,
只有当你得到 自觉时这才成为可能
when you get your collective consciousness, when you become baptized.
当你得到集体意识 当你受到洗礼
Before that it's only mental activity,
在自觉之前 这只是思维上的活动
quarrelling, fighting and living on artificial things.
争吵、战斗 以人工化的事物为食
How long are you going to do like that?
你还准备像这样行事多久
Your forefathers did it and their forefathers did it and their
你的祖先这样做过 其他的祖先这样做过
forefathers have done it.
祖先的祖先也这样做
Now is it not time for you
现在对你而言
to see that a new age has come?
难道不是一个看见 新时代来临的时候吗
What are you going to lose by that?
你打算失去什么
You form organizations
你成立组织
false and false and false.
一个个的错误
There should be some honesty about it.
这里应该有一些真诚
Just talking talking morning till evening,
只是从早到晚不断地谈论
you are not going to receive any knowledge about Christ I can tell you.
我告诉你，你将不会得到 有关于基督的任何知识
This narrow vision of Christianity
基督教的这种狭隘的眼光
has killed Christ and Christianity good.
杀死了基督和基督教
The narrow vision of Jews
犹太教的狭隘的眼光
has killed Moses and Abraham.
杀死了摩西和亚伯拉罕
The narrow vision of Krishna
Krishna宗教的狭隘眼光
and the narrow vision of all these people
以及所有这些人的 狭隘眼光
has killed them.
杀死了他们
They have dead in them. Your children are going to challenge you.
他们在这些宗教之中死去了 你的孩子将会向你挑战
They are going to ask you,
他们将会问你
what foolish things you have been doing all your lives.
你一辈子都做了 什么些愚蠢的事啊
They are going to ask you why did you do it?
他们将会问你 为什么你要这么做
Have you any answer to give?
你能给出任何答案吗
For that one has to understand
为了这点，一个人 必须要明白
that we have now found our absolute.
我们已经找到了 我们的至高无上
You be honest yourself. Have you found your absolute?
你要对你自己真诚 你找到了你的至高无上了吗
We have not yet found our absolute.
我们还没有找寻到 我们的至高无上
That's what you have to find.
这是你们必须要去寻找的
You are to be born again. Not to certificate yourself that
你需要得到重生 不是说你要给自己证书
I am born again. I have seen many people,
说我重生了 我见过许多人
I am born again. Really? How do you say?
我重生了，真的吗 你何出此言
Can you feel the chakras of another person?
你能感觉到 他人的轮穴吗
Are you collectively conscious? Can you feel your own chakras?
你有集体意识吗 你能感觉到自己轮穴的状况吗
Can you clarify yourself is there any
你确定你自己发生了转变
Then you have among Jews also
然后你置于犹太人
very fanatic people. Muslims
以及非常狂热的人之中
have lost
甚至失去了
even the recognition of God's
对上帝的
mercy and compassion.
慈悲和怜悯的认同
It is such a sad state. At this
这是如此可悲的状态
sad state and confusion,
在这种可悲的状态 和混乱中
there has to be
必须
the integrating force.
要有整合的力量
And that integrating force is your Spirit.
这个整合的力量 就是你的灵
That integration takes place in this seventh chakra of Sahasrara.
整合在这第七个轮穴 也就是顶轮中发生
All the seven centers are there
所有7个能量中心都在那儿
and all the centers are coordinated and co-related
所有的能量中心都是并列的 且息息相关的
and that's how, at the seventh chakra only you can get your Realization.
这就是为什么在第七个轮穴 你才能得到你的自觉
He didn't allow any one of them
他不允许其中的 任何一个人
to say anything about it.
去谈论它的任何事
If they try to say anything you brake bright out of the book,
如果他们尝试说任何事情 你拿出来书本
oh see this book is written it is written
噢你看这本书写了
in so and so and this is written so and so.
它是这样写的 是如此这般被描述的
Say for example when Christ was born.
举个例子 当耶稣出生的时候
It was said that
有人说
a child will be born to a girl.
一个小孩将在 一个女孩中出生
Kanya. In Sanskrit language it's Kanya.
kanya 在梵文中这是kanya
Now in England there was a controversy about it,
现在在英国 有一个关于它的辩论
Now I think the Jews started it maybe, I don't know who started it.
我猜可能是犹太人发起的 我不知道是谁开始的
Or maybe the Muslims.
也可能是穆斯林
God only knows. They go into all these details of that thing to find out
上帝才知道 他们钻到细节里
they said it was not said
试图找出 它不是说耶稣会生于童贞女
So one of the Sahaja yogi wrote a nice letter to them,
所以一个霎哈嘉修行者 写了一封友好的信给他们
of course under my guidance
当然是在我的指导下
saying that
信里面说
at the time when Christ was born, even before that,
在耶稣出生的年代 甚至在那之前
this prophecy was made and that time,
这个预言就已经有了 并且在那个时候
a girl meant a virgin.
一个女孩就意味着是童贞女
These are not modern times when
那不是在现代
a woman who is divorced
一个女人离婚了十次八次
is her age, and she's still called as 'my girl'.
还可以被叫做 我的女孩
These are foolish stupid modern times
这是愚蠢的现代
where there's no difference between a girl and a woman.
一个女孩和一个妇女之间 没有什么区别
That time a girl meant,
在耶稣的时代 一个女孩意味着
even today in India, Kanya means a virgin.
即使是在印度的今天 kanya也是童贞女的意思
Girl means a virgin. It's the same thing.
女孩意味着童贞女 这是一回事
All such things have been raised against
所有类似的事情发生着
either Christ or Moses or Mohammad or this and that.
违背着耶稣或摩西 或穆罕默德
I mean there only busy
我是说这只是忙于
raising things against each other, that's what they are doing.
彼此之间进行反对 这就是他们正在做的
According to them, what they say is the truth? What have they found?
根据他们
First thing, can they cure cancer?
首要的 他们能够治愈癌症吗
Let's see, let's have this challenge.
让我们看 让我们有这个挑战
Can they give peace to anyone? Are they peaceful?
他们能给予任何人以平安吗 他们是平安的吗
Have they been able to get over their adulterous eyes?
他们是否能够克服 他们邪淫的眼睛
Any transformation?
有任何转变吗
Nothing.
没有
So accept it. Be honest with yourself.
所以接受它 对你自己真诚
You have no business to cheat yourself, or anything whatsoever.
你没有权利欺骗你自己 或其他任何事情
If you are hypnotized
如果你被施催眠术
arise and find what is the best,
站起来找到 什么是最好的
absolute and the only thing that you have to find, your Spirit.
纯粹的而且是唯一 一件你需要找寻的事
Your Spirit resides in the heart.
你的灵居住 在心脏的位置
It is the reflection of God Almighty.
它是全能上帝的反应
It enjoys itself, by itself.
它享受它自身
It is the spectator of the world, of its power,
它是世界的旁观者 带着它的力量
The Holy Ghost.
圣灵的力量
It watches you
它守候着你
and is called as the knower of the fate.
它是命运的知者
It knows what you are doing,
它知道你正在做什么
what are your aspirations,
你渴望些什么
what mistakes you are committing.
你正在犯下什么错
It goes to a long extent
它在很大的程度上
to forgive and forgive and forgive.
去原谅、原谅、原谅
Forgiveness is one of the qualities of the Spirit.
原谅是灵的素质之一
It forgives you
它原谅你
and says it will work out.
并且它将会做到
It will come around.
它会回来
But when you go too far,
但是当你走得太远
say if you pay too much attention to your physical being
如果你太关注 你的物质存在
or to your mental being,
或者你的心理存在
if you try to think too much,
如果你试图思考太多
the Spirit indicates its displeasure
灵会表示不满意
and you get a heart attack.
然后你得了心脏病
Heart attack comes to you
心脏病通过
through displeasure of the Spirit.
灵的不满意而到来
If the Spirit is angry with you, you get a heart attack.
如果灵对你感到生气 你心脏病发作
That means you've neglected your Spirit,
这意味着 你忽略了你的灵
you've paid attention to things
你对不重要的事情
which are not important.
关注太多
You have looked after things which are not important.
照顾得太多
You have not worried about yourself, about the Spirit, about your seeking.
你不关心你自己，不关心灵 不关心你的追寻
Even if you're lost, say in any fanatic behavior
即使你迷失了
taking out certain things and remembering them by heart and
拿出一些东西 用心记着它们
having an argument and goes on later all that,
与别人辩论等狂热的行为中
in all genuineness and goodness
用所有的真心和好意 做这些事情
but stupidity then also you can get heart attack.
但是你也会心脏病发作
Heart is very important.
心脏是非常重要的
It sometimes gives you
有时候它会
first warning by giving you a partial paralysis
通过让你局部瘫痪 来给你第一次警告
because in the heart is sort of a,
因为在心脏中
a clot, and that clot when goes into the brain
当这个凝块走到 脑中的时候
you get a partial paralysis,
你得了局部瘫痪
so that you do not move any further.
所以你就不能再走动了
Your attention is taken to it.
你的注意力放在灵上
Then you start thinking of God,
然后你开始思考上帝
thinking of all the things
思考所有的事情
and maybe
可能
then if you come to Sahaja yoga you get cured
然后如果你来到霎哈嘉瑜伽 你得到痊愈
because again your Spirit forgives you.
因为再次地 你的灵原谅你
We are taking too much liberty with our Spirit.
我们对灵性太随便了
It is true God has given you freedom
上帝给予了你自由 这是真的
and He is not going to take away your freedom at any cost.
并且他无论如何 也不会拿走你的自由
You have to be absolutely free to choose
你有完全的自由去决定
whether to go to heaven or to go to hell.
是走向天堂还是走向地狱
He is not going to force you.
他是不会强迫你的
Only thing one can do
别人可以做的唯一一件事
is to explain to you and tell you
就是向你解释 告诉你
that this is the way you go to hell.
这是条通向地狱的道路
Even then if you want to go
即使之后你想要走向地狱
then what can anybody do about it?
谁能够对这做什么
Even God, He doesn't want to challenge your freedom at all.
甚至上帝 他一点也不想挑战你的自由
He doesn't want to make you, in any way
他不想以任何方式
bound to Him, like some people are,
让你束缚于他 就像一些人那样
bound just bound, without understanding.
约束就是约束 没有理解
But He wants your complete liberation.
但是他希望 你完全得到解放
So the first stage is that you have to choose your liberation
所以第一个阶段你必须 通过你自己对自由的选择
through your own freedom of choice.
来选择你的解放
Now, up to this point, till you were human beings,
在某种程度上 在你们成为人类之前
there was no choice for you,
你没有选择
but after becoming a human being
但是当你变成人类之后
you were given the choice because you could develop well
你可以有所选择 因为你可以在你自己的自由中
to understand what is right and wrong in your own freedom,
很好地发展出明白什么 是对什么是错的能力
so that you can enter into the Kingdom of God as
以便于
people
当人们是自由的
and in their own freedom.
选择了对的事物 你便可以进入上帝的国
This is the only small little step
这只是我们常常将自由 混淆于我们的自我的一个小点
For example, now,
举个例子，现在
this hall is here say, for me to speak.
这个大厅是在这里 我在演讲
Somebody comes from outside who has been sort of
一个人从外面走进来
worked up in some sort of an organization and
他曾经逐步创建了一个组织
he thinks he is doing the greatest work in the whole world in such a myth.
然后他认为他正在做 这个世界中最伟大的工作
Comes down here in that ego state,
他来到这儿 带着自我的状态
sits down here and asks me
坐下然后问我
questions after questions, questions after questions, questions after questions,
一个又一个的问题 一个又一个问题 接二连三的问题
doesn't allow anybody else to speak,
都不让别的人讲话了
takes away all my time to himself
把我所有的时间 都占用在他一人身上
as if this hall is booked by him and all the audience is gathered by him.
就好像这个大厅是他订的 所有的观众都是由他聚集的一样
He is least bother as to see
他至少打扰到能
that this is an ego that is working.
看到这是自我在工作
So we should not
所以我们不应该
confuse our freedom with ego,
将自由和自我混淆
that's what I have to give you a counsel.
这是我必须给予你的劝告
Try to differentiate your ego from your freedom.
尝试将自我 从你的自由中分辨出来
When you are ego bound, you are a slave of your ego.
当你被自我束缚 你成为自我的奴隶
When you are super ego bound,
当你被超我束缚
you are slave of your super ego,
你是你的超我 和条件制约的奴隶
For example, you are born a Christian, you are a Christian
举个例子 你出生于基督教家庭 你是基督教徒
you are bound forever then.
你就永远被基督教束缚着
All right, you are a Christian but what about real Christianity within you.
好吧，你是基督教徒
What about your rebirth in the real sense of the word.
得到重生这个词的 真正意义是什么
So you become enslaved to these things, so there is no freedom.
所以你被这些事情奴役 这里没有自由
And Spirit is
灵是
the freedom, is the free.
那个自由 灵是自由的
Being within us.
它在我们内在
It is detached.
它是超然的
It cannot be killed.
它不能被杀害
It cannot be blown away.
它不能被吹散
It cannot be burnt away.
它不能被烧毁
It is eternal. Anand. It is eternal.
这是永恒的喜乐 是永恒的
That Spirit is joy.
灵是喜悦
That Spirit is the source of joy.
灵是喜乐的源泉
That emits joy.
它散发出喜乐
Joy is different from happiness and unhappiness.
喜乐不同于快乐 或是不快乐
Ego, when it feels pampered, it feels happy.
自我被纵容时 便觉得快乐
I like it, I like it.
我喜欢这样
This "I" business
这个--我
is ego pampering
是自我得到了满足
that is no joy. Because you like to drink today
这不是喜乐 因为你今天想喝酒
and tomorrow you don't like to have a headache.
明天却不想头痛
It has the double side of I like and I don't like.
喜欢与不喜欢是 二元对立的
You like something through your ego, dislike through your super ego.
你因为自我而喜欢 因为超我而讨厌
So it is a one coin
所以这是 同一事物的两面
and there are two faces, one is happiness and another is unhappiness.
这两面，一面是快乐 一面是不快乐
Joy is beyond that. Joy is a drama
喜乐是超越其之上的 喜乐是一出戏剧
seer, is a witness. You see a drama. You know it's a drama going on.
先知是见证者 你看戏时知道这是在演一出戏
You just watch it as a drama. You're not involved
你只是在静观这出戏剧 不会陷入其中自拔
and you are seeing it and enjoying it.
你享受这出戏剧
You are crying if you see something, you're
你看到某些场景会哭 会流泪
weeping but you know you are not that, it's a drama.
但你知道这是一出戏剧
Seer, the witness.
先知是见证者
Your Spirit is the witness
你的灵便是旁观见证者
and when you become the Spirit
当你成为灵时
you become the witness.
你便可以旁观见证
You become the witness. For example,
你会成为旁观见证者
There is something exists in the window for example.
就像是它们只存在于窗外
Now you enter inside the room and you see through the window.
而你在屋里透过窗子向外看
Your conditioning is like one way arising in you as a thought,
制约就好像 是你的一个念头产生
which comes from the past.
它来自于过去
It rises again and another thought comes up and goes
它再次升起来 另外一个想法也出现
in the past.
然后成为过去
First the past thought is there and
首先过去的想法在那儿
then another future thought is there it disappears.
然后另外一个未来的想法 也在那儿，它消失了
You see the thought rising but you can't see a disappearing of the thought.
你看见想法升起 但是你看不到这个想法的消失
In between that is the present.
两个想法之间的空隙就是当下
That's the place is established, that present
这是当下所处的位置
is established
当你的注意力被灵所启发
when your attention becomes enlightened by the Spirit.
当下就会建立
Either you think of the future or of the past.
你不是思考着未来 就是思考着过去
But I say now. At this moment, at the present.
但是我说现在 在此时此刻，在当下
You cannot stand there
你不能保持在当下
because your Spirit is not enlightened.
是因为你的灵 没有受到启发
Because Spirit is the present.
因为灵就是当下
When you get your Realization,
当你得到自觉
you find that you are not thinking
你发现你不会 思考将来或过去
Everything becomes different.
每件事情都变得不同
The whole life becomes a drama
整个生活变成一场戏剧
and the joy out of it starts coming out
置于戏剧之外的喜乐 开始产生
and you really enjoy small, small things here and there
你真正享受每处的小事
and you really understand
你真正理解了
how much joy was lost before Realization.
在自觉之前 你失去了多少的喜乐
This is not a mental thing that gives you joy
这不是心理作用 给你了多少喜乐
but the joy pours on you from your head just like this,
而是喜乐就像这样 一样从你的头部倾盆而降
cool thing starts pouring down.
凉风开始倾泻
As some people have a feeling of a tension rising up,
就像一些人的紧张不安的 感觉升起时一样的感觉
it's the same way, a cool sort of thing,
一种凉凉的感觉
flow of joy you feel in your whole body pours out.
你在你的整个身体 感觉到喜乐之流倾泻而下
Sometimes this cool breeze that rises in the head
有时候这凉风从头部升起
also starts becoming like a fountain pouring down that joy within you.
然后变得就像泉水一样 将喜乐洒满你的全身
You look at the pictures, are examples see this star of Moses.
你看这些图片 它们是摩西之星的示例
You David star you see that
你看这个大卫星
when you see than you can think about it
当你看着它 而不是去思考它
or else just watch this.
或只是注视着它
Watch it and don't think.
注视着它，不要思考
The joy of the creation of that thing, whole thing,
创造的喜乐
Like all the creation around a lake
就像湖泊的创造
is completely felt in the lake
如果这个湖泊 没有涟漪的话
if the lake has no ripples.
这创造的喜乐 可以被湖泊完全地感知
Completely. In the same way, all that is joy,
完全地 同样的，所有的喜乐
the creator, whosoever it may be has put there.
造物者，不管它是谁 它都放置在这儿
You get the complete joy within yourself because there is no thought.
你在内在得到完全的喜乐 因为没有思虑
There is no barrier. No conditioning.
没有障碍，没有制约
The whole thing becomes one with you
所有的事情变得与你合一
and you start feeling extremely happy.
你开始感觉到极端的幸福
Extremely joyous.
极端的快乐
A feeling, which is indescribable.
这种感觉难以形容
It is to be just enjoyed,
只是去享受它
to be felt. Like Kabira was asked,
去感受它 就像卡比尔问过的
"Why don't you speak now?" So he says in Hindi language,
你为什么现在不说点什么 所以他用印地语表述
he is one of the terrific poets we have,
他是一位了不起的诗人
he says, "Jab mast huye to kya huye.
他说 Jab mast huye to kya huye
When I have gone into the nectar of the intoxication
当我们进入到 灵的狂喜的甘露中
of the Spirit, now what can I talk.
我们能说些什么 无法言语
no words can fill this meaning.
没有语言可以将其意义穷尽
You better be with me and get it and enjoy yourself."
你最好与我在一起 得到这喜悦并享受你自己
That's all he could say.
这是他能够说的全部
That's what I say, the narrow vision
这就是我说的 狭隘的眼光
has closed your eyes to so many things.
将你们的视野 局限在这么多的事情上
Even Christ you cannot understand.
即使基督你们也不能理解
About Christ it is written in Devi Mahatmya, about Maha Vishnu,
关于耶稣基督的事情 在女神颂中有描写 关于摩诃毗湿奴
all His life is written, if you can read it you can find out
以及他所有的生活都有被描述 如果你读它你将能够找到
that before coming on this earth you will see
在他来到这个世上之前
how He was created, what powers He was given,
他是怎样被创造的 他被赋予了什么力量
how He is the Son and all that is written.
他是怎样的儿子 所有这些都有被书写
But for us, only you think that Bible is the authority.
但是对我们而言 你只认为圣经才是权威
It is. But even to understand that Bible,
它确实是 但是即使是理解圣经
as I told you, to understand Gita you better get your Realization.
就像我告诉你们的 要理解薄伽梵歌 你最好得到自觉
In the same way to understand that Bible also
同样的，要理解圣经
you have to get your Realization.
你也必须得到自觉
The One about Whom
关于耶稣
it is described had never been to a school.
有描写到他从未上过学
None of them have been to any school.
他们中没有一个人曾上过学
For the first time in this life I have learnt this English language.
这辈子第一次 我学习了这个英文语言
I never knew this language in any one of my lives before.
在我之前的任何一世 我从未了解这个语言
Because I knew I have to talk to you.
因为我知道 我必须对你们讲话
And I have to tell you about Spirit in this language.
我必须用英文这种语言 告诉你们关于灵的事情
But to understand it we have to read ancient scriptures.
但是要理解它 我们必须要阅读古经文
Beautiful ancient scripture are there
美丽的古老的经文
which describes the nature of the Spirit.
描述了灵的本质
It is said that Spirit has got three qualities. Satchitananda -
古经文中描述了灵的三种特质 Sat Chit Ananda
Sat, chit, Ananda. Sat means truth,
存在，意识，喜乐 Sat的意思是真理
chit means attention.
Chit是指注意力
Anand means joy.
Anand是喜乐
Sat is the truth. What is the truth now?
Sat是真理 那么什么是真理
If you see something white it is the truth, all right.
如果你看见什么东西是白的 这是真理，那么好
But what is the truth of this shawl.
但是这个披肩的真理是什么
A realized soul can know
一个觉醒的灵能够知道
not you because his Spirit is enlightened.
而不是你 因为觉醒的灵是受到启发的
He sees the fifth dimension of this shawl.
他看到这个披肩的第五个向度
Let him hold it in his hands and he will know that this is Mother's shawl.
让他把披肩放在他手上 他就会知道这是母亲的披肩
Immediately he'll feel those cool vibrations coming out of it.
立刻地他将会感到到来自 这件披肩的清凉的生命能量
He'll know that this is Mother's shawl.
他将会知道这是母亲的披肩
That is the truth.
这是真理
The four dimensions, which we know of,
我们知道的有4个向度
is not the truth but the fifth one which is the truth, which is the Spirit.
它们不是真理，但是第五个向度 它是真理，它就是灵
Sitting down here you can find out anybody
坐在这儿你能发现任何人
what is he suffering from what are his problems,
他正在从他的问题中 承受怎样的痛苦
what are his chakras, it is absolute.
他的轮穴怎样 这是绝对的
This knowledge is absolute.
这个知识是绝对的
If you have five or ten children who are realized
如果你有5个 或者10个自觉的小孩
and if you tied her eyes
如果你蒙住他们的眼睛
and ask them about a patient,
问他们某个病人的状况
which is he suffering from, they will all raise their fingers
这个病人正在遭受着什么 他们都会举起他们的手指
this or this or this
这根或这根
or all of them,
或者所有手指
whatever maybe the case.
无论是哪一种情况
All of them will raise the same fingers
他们所有人 都会举起同一根手指
it is absolute knowledge.
这是绝对的知识
It cannot be argued.
没有争论
It cannot be refuted.
它不能被驳倒
It is what it is.
它是如其所如的
And also today the man may be having these
今天这个人可能有这些问题
problems tomorrow he may not have at all.
明天他可能 又没有了这些问题
So then whatever was there is finished
这样的话无论 问题是什么都完结了
whatever is today that's what they are going to tell you,
这些小孩会告诉你 今天你有的任何问题
so this is the truth. The rest is all
这是真理
I was once going in Kashmir
我曾经在去克什米尔的路上
driving through some very remote corner
开车经过一个非常偏僻的角落
and suddenly I felt tremendous vibrations in the air
突然我感到空气中 有巨大的生命能量
and I asked the driver
我问司机
"Is there any temple here or something?"
这个附近有庙宇什么的吗
because in Kashmir there are many temples which are vibrating.
因为克什米尔有许多的 庙宇散发着生命能量
So many things have come out of the Mother Earth,
如此之多的事物 从大地之母之处走出来
as it said in the Ten Commandment
如同在十诫中所说过的
that "Thou shalt not worship
你们不应
anything that is created by the Mother Earth,
任何来自大地之母的东西
reproduced and worshipped."
不应进行复制和崇拜
There are many in Kashmir like that.
在克什米尔有许多这样的庙宇
So, I asked him and he said "No there is no temple,
所以我问司机，司机说 没有，这里没有庙宇
there are no Hindus live in this area.
没有印度人居住在这片区域
I said but still I feel tremendous vibration
但是我仍然感受到 极大的生命能量
so my husband told driver "All right, let's go the way she says."
所以我丈夫告诉司机，好吧 让我们走她说的那条道
So, we followed about three miles
所以，我们行进了约3英里
and we reached a colony of people
然后我们到达了一个
who were Muslims living there.
穆斯林的聚居地
When we asked, "Is there any temple here?",
当我们问 这里是否有庙宇
he said, "No, but there is one great mosque."
他说，没有 但是这里有一个伟大的清真寺
"What mosque is that?" called as "Hazrat Iqbal."
是什么样的清真寺 它叫做Hazrat Iqubal
That means one hair of Hazrat Mohammad Sahib
意思是说 Hazrat Mohammad Sahib
of Mohammad Sahib one hair was there.
的一根头发在那儿
And even now to take His name, the vibrations start flowing.
即使现在提到他的名字 生命能量都开始流动
How can I deny Him?
我们怎能否定他
He was the truth.
他是真理
Spirit will not deny. It is the falsehood that denies
灵不会否认
It is the Spirit, that
是灵
gives you the truth, which integrates all that is truth
是灵给予你真理 它整合了所有的真理
and throws away that is untruth.
并摒弃了所有的不真实
That's why you must get your Spirit.
这就是为什么你必须成为灵
Before that anybody talks to you about God,
在你成为灵之前 任何人跟你谈论上帝
about anything they can even crucify.
谈论任何事情 他们甚至可以把你钉在十字架上
They are such stupid foolish people
他们是如此愚蠢愚昧的人
that they can do anything. They'll argue with you they'll
他们什么也做不了 他们会与你争论
fight with you, they'll do all kinds of stupid things but
他们会跟你打架 他们会做尽各类愚蠢的事情
This is what my father told me
这就是为什么 我的父亲告诉我
that you have to find out an en masse method,
你必须找到一种方法
method by which you give Realization to many people
通过它你可以 给与许多人以自觉
so that they can see that there is something beyond.
这样他们才能够 看到许多超越的事
They are all standing on the first floor
他们都是站在一楼的
if you are born on the tenth floor
如果你在十楼出生
and you tell them something that you see on the tenth floor,
然后你告诉他们一些 你在十层看到的东西
they're not going to believe you, they will fight with you, they'll
他们不会相信你 他们会跟你打架
quarrel with you, they'll pull you down
会跟你争论 他们会摧毁你
because their ego is challenged all the time.
因为他们的自我 始终受到挑战
So best thing is to transform them,
所以最好的事就是转化他们
give them en masse Realization.
给予他们集体的自觉
That is what is the Spirit is
这就是什么是灵
that every one of you have got Spirit
你们每个人都得到了灵的觉醒
but it was very difficult in those days to give en masse realization,
但是在开花结果的时代 还没有到来的时候
the blossom time had not come.
要给予集体的觉醒 是非常困难的事
Today the blossoms time has come.
但是现在 开花结果的时代已经来临了
And the wind that blows the cool wind
圣灵的凉风
gives Realization to so many of them.
给予如此多的人以自觉
Thousands of people have got Realization,
数以万计的人已经获得自觉
you also many of you have got your Realization.
你也是那许多 获得自觉的人之一
So this Spirit is established, you feel
因此灵已被确认 你感到
you are something different now.
现在，你是与众不同的
The transformation has started, the baptism has
这个转变已经开始
been done in the actual sense.
真正意义上的洗礼已经完成
and you start feeling its moving, you feel the cool breeze.
而你开始感受到它的流动 感受到这清凉的凉风
Now, when you take to your collective being, you become
现在 当你进入到整体的存有
You try to give.
你尝试去奉献
Now you are taking from me when I go, you stand here and give.
现在当我走了 你们从我这儿吸取力量 你站在这里向他人给予
When the light, the lamp is not enlightened,
当灯没有被点亮
then all right try to enlighten it.
那么好 尝试去点亮它们
After enlightenment what does the light do, is to give the light.
当灯被点亮之后 灯会做什么，它会给予光
Spirit gives you, your meaning.
灵给予你光 你的意义
Spirit gives you your understanding
灵给予你理解真理的能力
me you cannot understand if you are not Realized you cannot
如果你没有得到觉醒 你不能理解实相
I'm just like you, there is no difference.
我跟你一样 没有什么区别
But those who are Realized know about me very well.
但是对于那些已获自觉的人来说 他们对我了解得更深入
Even living in Ramuln.
即使在素不相识的人
A saint who met one of the Sahaja yoginis, she was American,
一个圣人遇到一个霎哈嘉瑜伽士 她是一个美国人
and he just bowed to her
他向她鞠躬
and made her sit higher than him and said, you have met Mother.
让她坐的位置高于他自己 然后说，你见过母亲
I have not yet met Her. And she was surprised
而我还没有见过她 她非常吃惊
that how did you know all these things.
为何他会知道这些事情
There are so many saints in India
在印度有如此多的圣人
who are real saints, who know about me.
他们是真正的圣者 他们知道我
But those who are very close to me also,
但同样有一些人 非常接近我
because you know my husband is highly placed in life
因为你知道我丈夫 在生活中是个成功人士
and we have friends of very elite and very...
我们有许多朋友是 精英人士
I have seen all prime ministers of the world,
我曾经见过世上 所有的总理
I've met them and I've met all sorts of kings and queens
我曾经见过他们 我也曾经见过 各种各样的国王和王后
and this and that and every day I am shaking hands with them.
见过这样那样的人 每天我与他们握手
They don't know me, they don't recognize me.
他们不认识我 他们不能认出我
There was a gentleman who we knew very well
有一个我们非常了解的绅士
he is now the President of the High Court,
他现在是高等法院的主席
World High Court
世界高等法院
and, I mean, we knew him very well
我是说 他在我们之中非常出名
a great friend of my husband's and all that,
我丈夫的一个伟大的朋友
and suddenly he saw, his wife saw my photograph with
突然他看到 他妻子看到
one of the Maharajas
我与另外一个王公的照片
place one of the Maharajas having in his pocket.
一个王公口袋里有这照片
So the Maharaja suddenly took it out the photograph and put it
所以那个王公 把照片掏出来看了看
to his eyes and put it back. So she said what is this?
然后又放回去 所以他的妻子问这是什么
Such and such lady, I know her very well.
这个女士，我知道她
He said yes, but don't you know she is
那个王公说是的 但是你不知道她
the Mataji, who has cured me of my heart trouble.
是Mataji，是她治好了 我的心脏的问题
She said, really? I didn't know she was a Mataji or anything.
她说，真的吗 我不知道她 是Mataji或任何人
She comes to the party, she's very quiet.
她来到聚会 非常安静
She just sits quietly.
非常安静地坐着
I never even heard her speaking.
我从没听过Mataji的演讲
For the last 25 years I know, she speaks very little.
在过去25年 她很少演讲
Oh God, she gives lectures and there are thousands of people.
噢上帝，Mataji做演讲 有成千上万的人在那儿
Can she speak?
她能演讲吗
She was surprised.
那个妻子非常吃惊
We have never seen her speaking anything.
我们从没见过她讲过什么
I won't even be able to recognize her voice even
我甚至不能认出她的声音
my husband of course speaks a lot and her husband speaks
即使我丈夫演讲了很多 她丈夫也演讲了很多
a lot, I also speak but I have never heard her speaking anything,
我也演讲了很多 但我从没听过Mataji 做过什么演讲 即使我丈夫演讲了很多 她丈夫也演讲了很多
she just keeps quiet, sometimes amusing to herself.
她只是保持安静 偶尔娱乐一下自己
She seems to be a dignified lady but otherwise
她看起来是一个高贵的女士
she never makes any efforts to impress us or anyway tell us that she is Mataji.
但是她从没做过 任何努力给大家留下印象 或者告诉我们她是Mataji
Immediately the husband got such a shock
立刻地她丈夫受到震撼
and he immediately telephoned to my husband,
他马上给我丈夫打电话
I never knew she was Mataji. It was such a thing.
我从不知道她是Mataji 事情是这样的
You knew I am a seeker, I'm a seeker, a seeker.
你知道我是一个求道者 我是求道者
And he said that. So my husband said she's now in Delhi, go and meet her.
他这样说 所以我丈夫说她现在在德里 去找她吧
Immediately he sent for me.
他便马上来找我
and he got his realization in five minutes,
他在5分钟内就得到了自觉
but his wife didn't get it. So he sent her back.
但是他妻子没有得到自觉 所以他就将她送回去了
He sent her by plane, that you better get it.
他用飞机将她送回 你最好得到自觉
This is the thing one has to get.
这是人们必须要得到的东西
Now the emphasis
现在需要强调的是
that you have to be your Spirit
你必须成为你的灵
is very much reduced
在现代社会中
in the modern society.
灵非常微弱
Emphasis should be that your Spirit
重点应该是 你应该在这一生
is to be achieved in this life time.
成就你的灵
This is what one has to do, is the
这是一个人必须要做的
only thing one have to do,
也是一个人唯一需要做的
that is not there in the western societies.
这在西方社会是没有的
Secondly for this you have to control your attention,
第二个要强调的就是 你需要控制你的注意力
don't allow your attention to spill out.
不要允许你的注意力 四处分散 第二个要强调的就是 你需要控制你的注意力
I hope I told you the story of
我希望我告诉过你 Janaka的故事
Janaka did I tell them I do not know but I'll again repeat
我告诉过他们吗，我不知道 但是我将再重复一次
Like there was a Raja Janaka, the father of Sita
有一个圣者Raja Janaka 他是Sita的父亲
father-in-law of Rama.
Rama的岳父
And Narada went to him,
Narada去找他
another celestial being, he went to see him and he said,
Narada是另外一个天国的仙人 他去看Raja Janaka然后说
"How is it, you are a king and you move about
这怎么可能 你是一个国王
like a king, you have everything like a king,
你行事像国王 你拥有国王拥有的所有东西
you have gold and everything
你有金子和一切事物
and how is it people say that you are [unclear]
人们怎么会说你是Videha呢
above all these things, above your body?
Videha是超越所有这些事情 超越你的身体
How is it?"
这是怎么可能的
He said, "All right, I will tell you in the evening,
他说，好吧 我将在黄昏些的时候告诉你
but just now you do me a job.
但是现在 你要帮我做一件事
You carry some milk in this pot."
你拿着这罐牛奶
The pot had no rim also.
这个罐子没有边缘
So poor fellow was carrying that.
所以这个可怜的家伙 一直扛着
The whole day he was carrying got tired.
整天他一直扛着非常地累
He said don't allow even a drop to spill out.
他说连一滴都不能洒出来
He was looking at it all the time.
他一直盯着
In the evening he got tired
到了晚上 他非常累
and put it there and he said, "Now will you tell me,
他把罐子放下来说 现在你可以告诉我了
I've had enough of this."
我已经受够了
He said, "What did you see when you were moving about?"
他说，当你走来走去的时候 你看到了什么
He said, "Nothing, what could I see? I was just watching
他说，什么都没有 我怎么可能看到
He said, "In the same way
他说 以相同的方式
I am at that stage where my attention does not spill out."
我在那个我的注意力 不会溢出的阶段
That is the state you are achieving
那是你们要到达的状态
your Self-Realization,
你的自觉
where the attention is completely enlightened by your Spirit.
注意力被你的灵完全地启发
It doesn't envelope anything like that
它不会像那样包裹一些事情
and even if it goes round it comes back as it is.
即使它转动它 也会像原来的样子回来
My hand when it touches it, it doesn't become this metal, does it?
我的手当它触摸它 它不会变成这个金属，是吗
It comes out.
它出来了
It's absolutely detached from this. I can touch it but I am not that.
它是从这完全地分离的 我可以触摸它 但是我不是那
Just now I am matter. I am everything,
现在我是物质 我是一切
I am worried about my children my house this thing,
我担心我的孩子我的房子 诸如此类的事情
but when I become realized
但是当我获得自觉后
I get completely detached.
我变得完全地分离
I am a spiritual living being.
我是一个属灵的生命
Then nothing
然后没有什么
can keep you down, nothing can dominate you.
可以让你下降 没有什么可以宰制你
And you do not dominate anything.
并且你不要宰制任何事情
That is the state of the Spirit. When that happens
那是灵的状态 当那发生的时候
you become beyond dharma sustenance, you are beyond it.
你变得超越正法 你超越它
For example there is no temptation for such a person.
对于这样的人 这儿没有试探
There's no temptation.
没有试探
There is no mental activity either
没有思想活动
there is no stealing nor telling lies. Such a person is extremely
没有偷盗 没有撒谎
like Christ. He had nothing to do with the prostitute.
像耶稣 他与妓女没有一点关系
I mean she was a different style, He was a different style.
我是说她是不同的风格 而耶稣是完全不同的另外的风格
But when people started stoning the prostitute
但是当人们向 妓女投掷石头时
He stood up before them and asked,
他站起来，站在他们前面 问他们
who are the ones who have not committed the sin?
你们谁没有犯过任何的错误
They could have stoned Him.
他们也有可能会向他扔石头
This His honesty and His strength stopped it.
他的诚实和力量制止了它
They will stand by all those who are tortured
他们会站在那些 受压制他人的人所折磨
and troubled by people who are oppressive.
和麻烦的人的身旁
They are not afraid of anything. They are fearless people.
他们不惧怕任何事情 他们是完全无畏的人
Neither they frighten anyone. They are compassionate.
他们不惧怕任何人 他们就是慈悲
But when it comes to protesting
但是当需要抗议时
they stand up fearlessly against those
他们大胆地站出来
There is no oppression. Even
没有压迫
I cannot argue it out with you. It has to work out.
我不能与你辩论 它是必须要成就出来的事
It is as simple as that.
就是这样简单
If you do not want it, you can never get it.
如果你不想得到自觉 你就不会得到它
Out of question.
毫无疑问
So there is [unclear] as I say, if you do not want it, you better go away
如我所说的 如果你不想要它 你最好离开
But still some obstinate people will sit there. No, I'll sit here. For what?
但是仍然有一些顽固的人 将会坐在这里
Such people also give out very bad vibrations to others
这样的人会给他人 发出很差的生命能量
and they disturb others getting their Realization, it is satanic.
他们会妨碍其他的人 得到自觉
Still I make them sit all right sit down.
尽管如此 我让他们坐下来
You cannot force it.
你不能强迫它
It's a light within you a flicker.
它是在你的内在闪现的一束光
And the analogy could be, like the gas.
可以这样做个比喻 就像燃气一样
That rises and touches the flicker and the whole gas gets enlightened.
随着火星上升 全部的气体都被引发
The flicker is awake all the time and watching.
看这火星一直在燃烧
Then the whole thing becomes the truth.
然后这整个事件变成了实相
Truth is very different from what we know as truth.
这个实相不同于 我们所知道的那个实相
Is a new dimension, by which we know
它是一个新的层面 我们通过它了解到
this is the truth and this is not the truth.
这是实相以及这不是实相
You can ask any questions when you are
你可以问任何问题
Ask the question about me.
问有关我的问题
Then ask the question about Christ,
然后问关于基督的问题
about Moses, about God. Ask any question.
关于摩西，关于上帝 问任何问题
And when the answer is yes, you will get cool breeze coming into you.
当答案是肯定的 你会获得凉风
If you aks any negative questions,
如果你问其他 消极负面的问题
you lose your vibrations. Might get tingling, might get heat.
你便失去了你的能量 可能会有刺痛，可能会热
Because now your computer is connected with
因为现在你的主机
This is a new awareness you get by which
你获得了一个新的知觉状态
you become aware
你变得可以认识到真理
Through vibrations a child also can know.
通过生命能量 一个小孩也能够知道
There are many children who are born realized.
有许多小孩是天生自觉的
And they know where is the Kundalini.
他们知道kundalini在哪儿
They know. They will tell you where is the Kundalini.
他们将会告诉你kundalini 在哪儿
It's the truth.
这是真理
Because they know the truth. For that you don't need
因为他们知道真理
too much of mental development.
为知道真理你不需要 有太多智力上的发展
They are very dignified.
他们是非常高贵的
They understand it better than many elderly people and
他们比许多年长的以及 许多在生活中有很高地位的人
Christ has already said
耶稣曾经说过
that rich men are not going to enter into the Kingdom of God.
富人不能进入到天国
He has already said because they are running.
他这样说是 因为他们跑掉了
But I would say even those who think they know a lot,
但我要说即使那些 认为自己知道很多的人
all knowing, they will not enter.
他们也不会进入天国
Because they do not want to enter.
因为他们不想进入
They know everything. They do not want to enter inside.
他们知道一切事 他们不想进入到里面
They want to carry their mind everywhere.
他们想随身携带 他们的头脑到任何地方
They want to carry their car inside the hall.
他们想要扛着车进入到大堂
How they will enter inside?
他们怎能进入到里面
They are not willing to keep their mind outside
他们不想要将头脑放置在外
because they are always dependent on that mind
因为他们经常依赖于这个头脑
which has given them nothing.
头脑没有给予他们任何东西
But to achieve Spirit you have to come there ego-lessly, to receive.
但是要成为灵 你必须没有自我地去接受
The light of your being
你存在的光
is going to enlighten the whole thing. Your temple.
将会启发所有的事 你的神殿
And when this light comes in,
当这个光进入的时候
when this line shines in you,
当它在你的内在闪耀时
then you can feel your collective consciousness, you can feel it,
你能感觉到你的集体意识 你能感觉到它
the cool breeze of the Spirit manifesting through you,
圣灵的凉风通过你展现出来
is described in the Bible in very short but deep.
这在圣经中有短暂 但非常深刻的描述
But, Adi Shankaracharya has written such a big book,
但是商羯罗写了一大本书
one is called as Saundarya Lahiri
这本书叫做《美之波流》 Saundarya Lahiri
or Chaitanya Lahiri.
或Chaitanya Lahiri
It is not easy to talk about all these in such a short time.
在这么短的时间内 要讨论这些并不容易
He wrote treaties of philosophy.
他写了一条条的哲学
Great personality he was
他有着伟大的人格
called as Vivekachudamani. First of all he gave
被称作为明辨力如皇冠珠宝 他第一次给予意识
conscious the call. Where is your conscience? Vivekachudamani.
这样的称呼 你的意识在哪儿 Vivekachudamani
Then he wrote many books and
然后他写了许多书
ultimately he wrote Saundarya Lahiri.
最后他写了《美之波流》
In that he says it's only the description of the beauty
在这本书中 他描述的都是灵量母亲的美丽
and in all details he has described nothing but The Mother.
他描述的所有细节 不是关于其他的 都是描写的灵量母亲
Her fingers, Her hands, Her movements and
她的手指，她的手 她的运动
everything and what he saw how the vibrations move in Her,
她的一切，以及他看见的 生命能量是如何在她之内移动的
every words that She speaks.
她所说的每一个字
You have to read that book to understand Sahaja Yoga.
为了理解霎哈嘉瑜伽 你必须要读这本书
It's very clearly given all these things.
所有这些都写得非常清楚
As I told you the other day, William Blake also has written about Sahaja Yoga
我有一天告诉过你们 威廉布莱克也写到了霎哈嘉瑜伽
very clearly.
非常清楚
But unless and until you have Realization
但除非你的自觉
you cannot know the truth. So He's the truth, "Sat".
你不能知道这真相 他就是真理
Then is "Chit" is attention, He's the attention.
然后Chit是注意力 他是注意力
Your Spirit is the attention.
你的灵是注意力
Attention of God.
神的注意力
God is attentive to you through your Spirit
神通过你的灵注意你
and when your attention is enlightened by Him
当你的注意力被神启发
that means you've come in the attention of God.
就意味着你已经来到 神的注意力之中
You are looked after by God. All His powers flow into you.
你得到神的照顾 他所有的力量流入你之中
All His protection comes to you.
他所有的保护都投向你
You will be amazed there will here Sahaja yogis will tell you.
你会感到惊讶 霎哈嘉瑜伽士们会告诉你
How they avoided accidents,
他们如何躲过意外
what happened after accidents
意外之后发生了什么
and miraculously how people are saved.
人们如何奇迹般获救
It is nothing new to me. It is the minimum that can happen to a person.
对我来说一点不新鲜 这是一个人 会遇上的最基本的事
This is the minimum of minimum,
这是最基本最基本的
because all the angels they take charge.
因为所有的天使们 他们会负责
You are on the stage, the angels are there to look after you.
你们在台上 天使们在那里照看着你们
And you really start gradually feeling the presence of that blessing
你真的开始慢慢 感觉到祝福的存在
which is the attention of God.
这是神的注意力
So He's the "Chit". " Sat", "Chit" and "Anand" He is the joy.
所以他是Chit Sat Chit 和Anand 他是喜乐
Because God is joy.
因为神就是喜乐
He created this universe
他创造了这个宇宙
not to make us serious and unhappy and sulky.
不让我们太严肃 不开心和沉闷
See how many flowers, how many beautiful things,
看看他为我们创造了多少花朵 多少美丽的事物
how many colors what He has created for us.
多少种颜色
For us to enjoy He has created all this not to indulge into nonsense,
为了我们能享受 他创造出所有的一切 不让我们陷入荒谬
into filth, into dirt,
陷入肮脏，污秽
the dirt of the mind, the sin
思维的污秽，罪过
the filthy ideas.
肮脏的想法
But to have a clean heart
而是让我们 有一个洁净的心
and to have a clean morality within us.
干净的道德
He has created this beautiful world for us to enjoy
他创造了这个 美丽的世界让我们享受
without that you cannot enjoy, you cannot enjoy
没有那个你无法享受 你无法享受
unless and until you have a clean morality within you,
除非你内在有干净的道德
you cannot enjoy yourself.
否则你无法享受你自己
And that joy is your own
那喜乐是你自己的
once you get your Realization.
只要你得了自觉
This joy is the compassion and grace of God.
这喜乐是神的怜悯和恩赐
When the Kundalini first rises
当灵量开始有
through one small little thread,
一丝升起
She touches the Brahmarandra here,
她在此触摸
just one thread.
仅仅一丝
She opens and the grace and joy.
她打开了 恩赐和喜乐
Because here is the seat
因为这里是 至高湿婆神的宝座
of Sadashiva, here is the seat of your Spirit.
这里是你的灵的宝座
When it touches the Spirit, that seat, the flow
当它触及灵，那宝座
of the grace starts coming
恩赐便开始涌来
on your sympathetic nervous system and you feel relaxed.
在你的交感神经系统处 你感到放松
First thing happens to you you feel relaxed.
最先发生的事情是 你感觉到放松
Is the grace. Only one thread has reached
这是恩赐 仅仅是一丝成就
and then the flow that is flowing today this one is the Brahma
现在流动的是梵
is the power of God flowing through you.
是神的力量流过你
This is what you have to get.
这是我们必须得到的
This is what you've to remember, somebody touched Christ and the power went.
这是你们必须记住的 有人触碰了基督 这个力量走了
For us
对于我们
it is necessary to know that we are the first Australians to get Realization.
必须知道我们是第一批 得到自觉的澳大利亚人
You are the first people to get it.
你们是第一批得到的人
And it's a great responsibility on you,
而这是你重大的责任
all of you who have got Realization today and before,
所有今天 和之前得到自觉的人
to keep it strong.
来保持它的强大
Make it into a tree, because you are responsible for
树立它成一棵树 因为你有责任
all the progeny that is going to come to this
对于后代将要来到的 这个美丽的土地
So this is the beautiful place
所以这是那个美丽的地方
and beautiful people. So many children of mine.
和美丽的人
Today is the last day.
今天是最后一天
It's a very sad thing that one has to say good-bye.
要说再见是非常难过的事
I hope you all will make it convenient to come and see me on Sunday.
我希望你们方便 能够礼拜天来见我
I'll be looking forward to you.
我期盼你们的到来
Here I will try to cure you also
这里我也会试治你
if you have any problems, but don't bring all the hospitals there.
如果你有任何问题 但是不要把 所有的医院带到这儿
I will teach you how to cure and how to give realization.
我会教你怎么治疗 和怎么给自觉
Best thing is you bring the case to me and I will tell you how to
最好的是你把案例带给我 然后我会教你怎么自己治疗
We always in India do,
在印度，我们经常
when a cancer patient comes in, we call
当一个癌症病人进来的时候
one of his relations, give him Realization, teach him how to cure cancer
我们会叫他的家属 给他自觉
and he looks after the patient.
然后让他照顾病人
Because that's the best way one can do it.
因为那是最好的方式
He can give Realization,
他可以给自觉
to that person he can look after better,
他可以更好地照顾那个人
he knows the person better
他更了解那个人
and it works out much better that way.
所以这样效果会更好
So I hope you'll make it convenient to come and see me.
所以我希望你能够 让自己方便来见我
I must say, I was very much impressed by Sydney people
我必须说 我对悉尼的人印象非常深刻
who have been so kind to come here and listen and get their Realization.
好心地来到 这里来听和得自觉
I have to say that
我要说
because I am a mother.
因为我是一个母亲
I cannot just leave it to your senses.
我不能就这样交给你们的理性
I have to ask, I have to request you.
我必须要求 我要请求你
I have to be very, very patient with you, extremely patient
对你我需要非常非常地有耐心 极其的耐心
and loving so that you listen to me
和充满爱地 好让你会听我的
and take your Realization. I have to actually
和得到自觉
It's all right, that is mother's job, only mother can do it.
这没有关系 那是母亲的工作 只有母亲可以这么做
When Christ will come, He will take His
当耶稣将到来 祂会带着祂的
eleven powers and He will just sort you out.
十一个力量来判断你
Before that please have yourself completely judged
在那之前 请完全地判断自己
through your own Kundalini awakening and work it out.
通过你自己灵量的觉醒来成就
Those people who have came with ideas
那些带着 自己主意来的人应该
just go and see for themselves what they have achieved by these
自己去看看通过这些主意
ideas.
自己成就了什么
There have been so many organizations, one after another.
接二连三地有了 那么多的组织机构
There is no way to organize God.
上帝是没有办法去组织的
Better organize yourself
最好组织自己
through your Spirit, which is the absolute.
通过你的灵 那是绝对的
May God Bless You!
愿上帝保佑你